langara.bc.ca 2019-12-16

# Langara. About Langara : Records Management and Privacy: Privacy: Privacy Statement

_Last updated: April 24, 2019  _

This website is covered by British Columbia’s _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_ (the Act).

###  **Scope**

This privacy statement describes the personal information Langara College collects via the College’s website and social media accounts and how we collect, use and disclose that information.

### **Personal Information**

Personal information is recorded information about an identifiable individual, such as an individual’s name, address, birth date, email address and phone number.

### **Collection**

Langara College is a post-secondary educational institution operating under the statutory authority of British Columbia’s _College and Institute Act_. The College collects personal information to establish and maintain a responsible relationship with you and provide you with ongoing service, to understand your needs and develop and recommend suitable products and services, to manage and develop our operations and to meet legal and regulatory requirements. Langara College is authorized to collect personal information via this website and social media under section 26(c) of the Act, for the purposes described above.

When you send us electronic mail, we collect your email address, your IP address and your message so that we may reply to you. If you send us sensitive personal information over the Internet or by email, we recommend that you encrypt the information prior to sending it.

When you visit our website, the web server collects a small amount of information to facilitate the operation and security of our website. This information may include browser type, Internet domain name, and IP address. Some information, such as your Internet domain name or IP address, may identify you. This information is not accessed by anyone outside of Langara College.

The website search function collects information to remember the information you submitted to search our website.

### **Cookies**

A cookie is a small file that a website creates when you visit the site. It can track and store information about you such as how and when you use a site and which site you visited immediately before. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Our website may use session cookies which are stored in temporary memory and are not retained after you sign out or close the browser session. 

Third parties may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect or receive information from Langara’s website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. You can opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting by visiting: [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

### **Web Analytics and Remarketing**

Langara College use web analytics tools on our website to collect data about site traffic to improve visitors’ online experience. These tools tag web pages to capture a limited amount of non-personal information such as the internet protocol (IP) address of the computer, device or network a visitor uses to access pages on the site. Langara College will never use this information for any reason other than to analyze site usage, or combine it with any personal information about you.

This site also uses remarketing tools to allow the College to serve previous visitors to our site with advertisements on third party websites (such as Google). Third parties, including Google, use cookies (small files stored on a computer’s web browser) to serve ads based on a person’s past visits to Langara’s website. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser (please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website). Some service providers also allow you to set preferences or opt out of interest-based advertising entirely, e.g., Google Ads: [Opt out of seeing personalized ads](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en).

### **Use**

Langara College only uses the personal information we collect about you from this website for the same purpose that we collected it. We will not use your personal information for another purpose without your consent.

### **Disclosure** (Sharing Your Information)

Langara College may only disclose your personal information for the same purpose as it was collected. We will not share the information for any other purpose without your prior written consent. The College may be required or authorized by law to disclose your personal information to another party in limited circumstances as outlined in section 33 of the Act.

### **Links**

Our website contains links to other sites and we provide these links as reference to help you identify and locate other Internet resources that you may find of interest.

### **Contact Us**

If you have questions about this privacy statement, please contact the Manager, Records Management and Privacy at 604-323-5660 or by email at [jrajotte@langara.bc.ca](mailto:jrajotte@langara.bc.ca). You can write to us at:

Langara College  
Records Management and Privacy  
100 West 49th Avenue  
Vancouver, BC    
V5Y 2Z6
